# Juan Lemos

Personal Information

Name: Juan Lemos Web: juanlemos.com

linkedin.com/in/juan-lemos



## Summary

Software engineer graduated from Universidad Católica del Uruguay. MBA student. Passionate about learning, making questions and solving problems. Interested in decision making and business management. I have worked for more than 4 years into the software development industry with American clients, in diverse teams. My tasks have been to align the software solutions with the client's needs and thinking in the medium- and long-term consequences.

#### Skills

### Programming:

- React
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- NodeJS
- SQL
- Django
- Swift

#### Others:

- English
- Decision making
- Communication
- **Problem-Solving**
- Scrum

# Experience

Freelancer | April 2021 - Present

Partner at AprendeFit | Mar 2020 - Present

Team leader at Octobot | Mar 2020 - April 2021

Full stack developer at Código Del Sur | Aug 2017 - Mar 2020

Scholarship at ICT4V (ANII) | Sep 2016 – Jul 2017

#### Education

IEEM Business school – MBA | 2021 - Present

IEEM Business school – PJP business programs | 2019

Universidad Católica Del Uruguay – Computer engineer | 2013 – 2017

## Accomplishments

Full tuition scholarship at Universidad Católica Del Uruguay – Decision making in business 2014

Tuition scholarship at Universidad Católica Del Uruguay 2013

### **Experience details**

Team leader at Octobot

Mar 2020 - April 2021

I have managed 5 projects with scrum methodology.

At the same time, I have been guiding teams of 8 people.

I was in charge of doing demos, planning, guide the team, negotiate, and manage client requirements. When I was not managing, I used to help the team with programming tasks in Django, SwiftUI, or ReactJS.

Full stack developer at Código Del Sur

Aug 2017 - Mar 2020

I have work on several projects with scrum methodology. I gave demos and developed with NodeJS and ReactJS technologies.

Scholarship at ICT4V (Information and Communication Technologies for Verticals) Sep 2016 – Jul 2017

This project was made in the context of a bigger project called "Prototipos evolutivos" (Evolutionary Prototypes), which is part of ICT4V (Information and Communication Technologies for Verticals) and was proposed by De Larrobla & Asociados Ltda (trade name: Bantotal). The goal of this project was to create a language useful to specify business bank processes, focused on those which are batch. This language would allow to specify the logic of calculations (low complexity) that must be done and be able to deduce and specify the way to access the data, with the aim of reducing the time of process execution. For example, using parallel computing and caching data.